this is an engulfing Candlestick and
this is exactly how much it's made me
today alone and I can refresh right now
my phone you guys can see I'm refreshing
live and this is how much It's Made Me
by using the engulfing Candlestick
strategy in under 24 hours and in this
video I'm going to show you the exact
strategy that I use to take this trade
and how you can use it for yourself as
well I'm going to explain to you how I
did it and how you can use the engulfing
Candlestick strategy for yourself you're
probably wondering what the engulfing
Candlestick is after seeing that and
it's actually very simple it's exactly
what it says in the name an engulfing
Candlestick is a Candlestick that eats
the last two Candlestick it is one
Candlestick that engulfs the last
previous two candlesticks this confirms
that it is a bullish engulfing
Candlestick or a bearish engulfing
Candlestick knowing how to properly use
this along with a lot of other stuff
that you add to your trading is more
than enough to have an edge in the
market and have a precise entry signal
which ultimately it's going to take you
to make a lot of money in trading but
obviously you got to combine that with a
winning risk management strategy and in
this video I'm going to share to you how
you can use this simple but powerful
approach to the market so you can make
money with it but before I actually
start explaining to you guys the
explanation I want to be very honest
with you guys this is a very simple
strategy but it is so effective that I
can't even explain it obviously you have
to factor in additions so you have an
edge in the market but you just saw how
with that simple entry engulfing
Candlestick I was able to make $54,000
and under 24 hours from my phone so now
that you understand that what is the
engulfing candles what is the pattern
what does it consist of and as you can
see right here in this picture it is a
three Candlestick pattern it consists of
two candlesticks headed in One Direction
and then you have one Candlestick headed
in the complete other direction this
right here is also known as a Morning
Star formation or a bullish engulfing
Candlestick here you can see how one
Candlestick engulfs the last two
candlesticks without the one Candlestick
and eating or engulfing the last two
candlesticks this would not count as a
bullish engulfing Candlestick and it
would not be a valid entry signal to use
as a bullish engulfing Candlestick and
now this example right here is basically
the same exact thing but now heading to
the downside you can see two
candlesticks heading to the upside and
then one big red Candlestick to the
downside this is a bearish engulfing
Candlestick as you can see the one red
candle has completely engulfed two Blue
candles heading to the upside indicating
that the market now is going to continue
to the downside so now that you
understand what gulfing Candlestick
consist of which actually very simple
and they're literally all over the chart
you can see them everywhere on any
single time frame once you're looking at
the market but now you're probably
wondering do these candlesticks always
mean the same thing can you always use
them as a reversal pattern at any point
in the charts and the answer is no you
can have a bearish engulfing Candlestick
in the middle of the chart and that
doesn't mean that price is going to
completely reverse at that point and
just because you have a bullish
engulfing Candlestick in the middle of
the price going up doesn't mean that
price can completely go against it this
engulfing Candlestick has to be used
correctly at a strong area of Interest
or at a strong supply and demand zone or
at a strong support and resistance they
are all the same thing at the end of the
day it's a base point where the
engulfing Candlestick is having a
rejection from whether it's to the
upside or whether it's to the downside
this engulfing Candlestick is most valid
and most powerful once it has a base
point to push off of not just in the
middle of the chart that it just
happened to pop up so if you're looking
to take advantage of the bullish
engulfing Candlestick or the bearish
engulfing Candlestick make sure that it
is at a level of support or level of
resistance if you want to know what a
strong level of support and resistance
and how do I identify those zones I have
a video for you right here that explains
it perfectly in addition with the
engulfing Candlestick strategy which is
a Perfect combo you need to make sure
that that you're at a strong support
level to use the bullish engulfing to
then buy you need to make sure you're at
a strong resistance level so then you
use the bearish engulfing to then sell
so I'm going to actually show you the
same example of this very trade right
now that I'm actually up
$53,000 this is the exact example of
what I'm trying to explain to you guys
right now so you guys can see right here
this is AUD Cad and how I have entered
on the 30 minute time frame after this
beautiful bullish engulfing Candlestick
so this is the classic bullish engulfing
Candlestick where it has completely
eaten the last two candlesticks and now
this candlestick has engulfed above the
last two candlesticks this right here is
a valid bullish engulfing Candlestick
this right here is an example of another
valid bullish engulfing Candlestick
which is known as a Morning Star
formation this right here on the other
hand is not a bullish engulfing
Candlestick simply because you can see
how they took two candles to eat the
last Red candle that is not the goal the
goal is for one whole whole entire
candle to eat the last two candles as it
did here as it did here this case over
here is also not a bullish engulfing
Candlestick even though it completely
ate one this Candlestick right here
should have eaten above this point right
here so this is a perfect example of
what is a bullish engulfing and what is
not a bullish engulfing so now how do
you take a trade based off of a bullish
of bearish engulfing very simple and it
goes back to the point how I just
mentioned you need to be at a strong
level of support support and resistance
the strong level of support and
resistance as you can see right here is
my 4-Hour level of supply and demand
support and resistance a of Interest
again it's all the same thing so as you
can see here this is a support or
resistance level where price whenever
it's above it's being held to head to
the upside whenever it is under it is
pushing price to the downside as you can
see right here so a valid level of
support and resistance is a Zone where
it has more than three touches this
obviously has more than three touches so
now once you find this strong level of
support and resistance I go to the lower
time frames such as a 30 minute 15
minute and I'm looking for this bullish
engulfing Candlestick along with a lot
of other little details but the main
priority is this bullish engulfing
Candlestick as you can see right here I
got this engulfing Candlestick at 9:30
in the morning placed my entry as soon
as that Candlestick closed and I put my
stop loss right under the low of the
last two candlesticks and I give it some
breathing room just in case if it needs
to come back and then create some type
of Wick so price can fluctuate because
obviously the market simply has to
breathe so after I take the trade next I
have to place my takeprofit and then
this is a trade where I have multiple
take profits set up because you guys
know I'm a day trader into day trader
swing Trader really depends on the type
of approach that I want to do based off
the account but it's the same exact
strategy that I use on every single
account it's just do I want to hold the
trade longer or not and for this example
right here this is a prime example of an
intraday trade that I can turn into
potentially a swing trade simply because
my first takeprofit was this structure
level right here on the daily time frame
which was the high of this Wick and on
the same time frame that I entered it's
the highest point that it did right here
which is a nice Zone very valid but
looking at the higher time frames
looking for continuation of the market I
noticed that we have a very strong level
of support and resistance right here you
can see we have one two three touches
and there's pretty much nothing stopping
price to getting to that point right
next to it the last point over here
there's nothing stopping it as you can
see price hasn't been up here in over 6
months so now that we're back at this
point right here it's pretty much Clear
ways for it to hit this structure point
right here and I can stretch my profits
from where I am right now all the way to
this point and I can literally double my
profits right now where I'm up exactly
$49,000 so if it goes right up to here I
can make it anywhere from $75 to $80,000
on this trade alone but don't always
fall for this Candlestick this can
actually be very misleading at a lot of
times and a lot of Traders can get
caught in the wrong side of this bullish
engulfing or bearish engulfing
Candlestick so for example let's say
right here we were looking to enter a
trade based off of a bullish engulfing
Candlestick and you wanted to take it
thinking that it was a valid trade
sometimes that's not the case and it
actually doesn't go in your favor for
example this trade right here as you can
see this is a very valid bullish
engulfing Candlestick and has actually
eaten more than the last two
candlesticks it has eaten about 10 of
them so it's eaten a lot of price in
just one single Candlestick which is a
very strong indication that price should
now continue to head to the upside but
guess what you just did you literally
just bought right at a resistance level
as you can see this is the level of
support and resistance that whenever
we're above we're buying and whenever
we're under we're selling that that is
why it's so key to enter the trade at a
very key support or resistance level I
can almost guarantee you if this bullish
engulfing happened above the zone so for
example like this this trade would have
had a completely different turnaround
because of right now you're literally
having that bullish engulfing
Candlestick directly into a resistance
level and you don't want to do that if
you're buying at a bullish engulfing you
want to be above a support level and if
you want to be selling with a bearish
engulfing you want to be under a
resistance level this right here is
another example of a Rand bearish
engulfing Candlestick that just happens
in the middle of the chart and you
should stay away from these because they
have no context and they have no
business this right here is a simple
bearish engulfing Candlestick it
obviously didn't eat completely the last
two candles so that should be your first
red flag and on top of that it kind of
just happened in the middle of the chart
there's no valid level of support and
resistance obviously there is on the 30
minute but with the set foret strategy
we don't use 30 minute areas of interest
because they're nowhere near as
effective as the time frames that we use
with the strategy so this this is
another example of what you want to stay
away from because it is not valid it's
simply in the middle of the chart with
no context and this engulfing
Candlestick pattern I wish I learned at
the beginning of my journey it would
have saved me so much time trying to
figure out what worked and what didn't
but it's not enough once you learn this
pattern you still need to have an actual
trading plan to be able to execute that
engulfing Candlestick with some type of
trading plan with the center foret
strategy UNS Traders make anywhere from
,000 to $1,500 a week as a beginner set
and forget Trader we've been trading for
about 6 years in the market and I have
perfected the engulfing Candlestick
strategy along with the set and forget
trading plan which leads traders to make
anywhere from ,000 to $1,500 a week as a
beginner set and forget strategy and
you're probably wondering what do set
and forget mean and how does it let
people make anywhere from ,000 to $1,500
a week just click the link in the
description below I have a video there
for you that explains exactly what the
center is and what it consists of every
single week I got on a call with the
students and we ident toy these same
patterns every single week and how you
can use the set and forget strategy to
your advantage in correlation with the
engulfing Candlestick confirmation so
you add it with the trading plan so if
you want to know what set of forget is
and how I let Traders make anywhere from
,000 to $1,500 a week click the link in
the description below I have a video
there for you that explains everything
to Perfection and I appreciate you guys
watching this video all the way to the
end I'll see you guys in the next video